Guide to the James Morrisey Papers WAG.158
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
James Morrisey Papers
Bulk, 1968-1969
1934-1973
WAG.158
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
1.0 linear feet in 1 record carton
James Morrisey joined the National Maritime Union in 1941, and remained an active seaman for over 30 years. Morrisey was the Chairman of the Committee for NMU Democracy and edited the Committee's newsletter The Call. The collection includes correspondence to The Call, as well as clippings, flyers, meeting mintues and notes.
Morrisey, James.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Historical/Biographical Note
James Morrisey joined the National Maritime Union in 1941, and remained an active seaman for over 30 years. Morrisey was critical of the leadership on the NMU, led by Joseph Curran. In addition to serving as the Chairman of the Committee for NMU Democracy, Morrrisey also edited the Committee's newsletter The Call. Morrisey ran for union office twice, in 1966 and 1969, losing both times. In the 1970s Morrisey initiated a series of lawsuits on behalf of the NMU rank and file claiming misappropriation of funds by the union leadership.
Scope and Contents note
This collection contains materials relating to the National Maritime Union, and particularly the rank and file Committee for NMU Democracy. The collection includes correspondence to the Committee's newsletter, The Call, as well as clippings, flyers, meeting mintues and notes. There is also material pertaining to NMU elections, and the NMU convenetion in 1969. The lawsuits initiated by Morrisey in the 1970s are not represented in this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown. The accession number 1950.061 is associated with this collection.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Curran, Joseph Edwin, 1906-1981; National Maritime Union of America.; Labor union democracy |z United States.; Merchant mariners |z United States
- Clippings (Seamen's Strikes), 1934-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Clippings (Selma, Alabama), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Flyers, Notices, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Maritime Policy, 1965-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Membership Meeting Minutes, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- National Martime Union Convention, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- National Maritime Union Election, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)